Register of the John Topp Brother Company Records, circa 1873-1958
Wisconsin Historical Society
John Topp Brother Company Records, circa 1873-1958
John Topp Brother Company (Columbus, Wis.)
M70-384
2.1 c.f. (3 archives boxes and 2 flat boxes) and 27 volumes
Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division
Records, circa 1873-1958, of the John Topp Brother Company dry goods and grocery store, primarily consisting of financial records, including retail account and supplier ledgers, cash books, and receipt and disbursement journals. Also included are a meeting minute book, annual inventories, sample stock certificates, and an appraisal report of John Topp's estate.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Presented by Russel Moore, Columbus, Wisconsin. M70-384
Contents List
- Appraisal report, John Topp estate, 1934, M70-384 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Sample stock certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Legal and financial papers, miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Item selling prices (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Maximum prices for cost of living commodities, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annual inventories, 1915-1918, 1942, undated (Box 1, Folder 6-12)
- Meeting minute book, with financial reports, 1917-1948 (Volume 1)
- Cash journals
  - 1898, September - 1908, May (Box 4, Volume 2)
  - 1891, September - 1896, October (Volume 3)
  - 1896, October - 1900, October (Volume 4)
  - 1906, October - 1912, October (Volume 5)
  - 1912, October - 1916, September (Volume 6)
  - 1916, September - 1917, July (Volume 7)
  - 1917, July - 1918, February (Box 4, Volume 8)
  - 1941-1947 (Box 4, Volume 9)
  - 1948, October - 1958, August (building account book) (Box 5, Volume 10)
- Daily receipt and disbursement journals
  - Circa 1894-1899 (Volume 11)
  - 1921, January - 1922, April (Volume 12)
  - 1923, January - 1924, May (Volume 13)
  - 1924, May - 1925, September (Volume 14)
  - 1925, September - 1926, December (Volume 15)
- Merchandise account book (payments to suppliers), 1901-1909 (Box 5, Volume 16)
- Purchases
  - 1922, April - 1924, November (Volume 17)
  - 1924, December - 1926, December (Volume 18)
- Retail accounts ledgers
  - Circa 1873-1875 (Volume 19)
  - Circa 1874-1877 (Volume 20)
  - Circa 1876-1879 (Volume 21)
  - Circa 1877-1880 (Volume 22)
  - Circa 1879-1884 (Volume 23)
  - Circa 1881-1887 (Volume 24)
  - Circa 1884-1887 (Volume 25)
  - Circa 1887-1890 (Volume 26)
  - Circa 1889-1892 (Volume 27)
  - Circa 1891-1896 (Volume 28)
  - Circa 1892-1897 (Volume 29)
  - Circa 1907-1912 (Volume 30)
- Suppliers' ledgers
  - Circa 1908-1913 (Volume 31)
  - Circa 1916-1919 (Box 2)
  - Circa 1919-1924 (Volume 32)
  - Circa 1924-1926 (Box 3)
- Accounts ledger, payable and receivable
  - 1917, July - 1926, December (Box 3)
- 1941-1948 (building account book) (Box 5, Volume 33)
- Summary account book, general ledger, journal, bank statements and checks written, 1951-1952 (Box 3)